（设想）在2024年，太空叉准备送人类去火星
In the year 2024, SpaceX aims to send the first humans to Mars
这离人类第一次登月已经过去55年了
55 years after man first set foot on the moon
在阿波罗工程中，人们登月只会停留几天的时间
While the Apollo missions only involved short stays on the moon
而太空叉的计划是把火星变成人类的永久居所
SpaceX aims to make Mars a permanent home for humans
人类第一批前往火星的宇航员大约需要五个月才能抵达
For the first group of astronauts heading to Mars, the journey is expected to take around 5 months
但他们到了一后要干嘛呢？
but what will they do when they get there?
本期视频我们来讲讲送人类去火星之前的准备工作
In this video, we’re going to look at what needs to be achieved before we can send humans to Mars
以及殖民火星初期需要建设的设备与系统
We are also going to look at the initial structures and systems
that astronauts will set up in order to begin colonizing Mars
在宇航员真正登上火星之前
Before the first astronauts ever set foot on the surface of Mars
需要提前准备一些基础的保障设备，比如水和能源
they will need to have the essentials like water and power already set up before they get there
太空叉打算在2022年的窗口期送两艘无人BFR飞船
SpaceX plans to achieve this in 2022 by sending two BFR’s on uncrewed missions
其上携带大型太阳能板与采矿系统等重要设备
carrying important equipment such as: a large array of solar panels and a mining system
采矿系统是太空叉自动燃料工厂的基础
This mining system will be the basis of SpaceX’s automated propellant plant
他们打算每次火星任务都拓展燃料工厂的规模
which they aim to expand with every new mission that heads to Mars
燃料工厂会收集火星上大量的水和二氧化碳
This propellant plant will process the large supplies of CO2 and Water found on Mars
然后利用萨巴捷反应生产氧气和甲烷
by using the Sabatier process to make Oxygen and Methane
再将其液化制成燃料，供宇航员返回地球使用
which will then be liquified and used as fuel to return the astronauts back to Earth
如果这些在人类殖民前的基础设施建设顺利的话
If this mission is successful in setting up the foundations for a Mars colony
太空叉将在2024年送第一批人类前往火星
SpaceX will be oncourse for sending the first humans to Mars in 2024
该任务包括两艘货船和两艘载人飞船
This mission will consist of 2 cargo ships and 2 crewed ships
每艘6到8名宇航员
carrying around 6 to 8 astronauts each
宇航员会在火星某处待上几个月或几年
The astronauts could be staying on Mars anywhere between a few months or a couple of years
那段时间里他们将继续建设燃料工厂
while they continue to set up the propellant plant
宇航员抵达以后必须做的最重要的事是建立基地
One of the most important things the astronauts will have to do when they arrive is set up a base
现在还不太好说第一个火星基地是什么样
It’s unclear what the first Martian base will look like
虽然据说可能有和国际空间站类似的设计
although many have suggested that it should have a similar design to the International Space Station
有可折叠的加压舱，可以充气成一个房间
with compact pressurised modules, allowing room for expansion
但还有说火星的第一个基地应该建在地下
Others have suggested that the initial base on Mars should be built underground
来保护宇航员免遭火星的宇宙辐射和极端天气影响
to protect the astronauts from the intense radiation and extreme weather experienced on Mars
这样一来马一龙的无聊公司（挖地铁那个）或许能派上用场
It’s possible that Elon Musk’s Boring Company could be used
派几个工程师去挖地道，为宇航员在火星建设地下居所
to dig tunnels and create underground habitats for astronauts to live on Mars
另一个问题是宇航员吃啥
Then there is the question of how astronauts will get their food
第一批去火星的宇航员会带满两年的真空包装食物
The first astronauts on Mars will take a 2 year supply of vacuum sealed packets of food
这些食物很轻，而且不占地方，和空间站使用的一样
which are light and compact, just like the ones used on the ISS
宇航员不会依赖火星种植的食物
The astronauts won’t be relying on Mars grown food
然而他们很有可能在第一次任务中就带去一个温室
however it’s likely that they will bring a greenhouse on their first mission
来试验种植食物与将其作为食物供给的可能性
to experiment with growing food and possibly supplementing their food with freshly grown produce
作为登上火星的宇航员
In order to navigate the surface of Mars
除了有房，还得有车，才能应付火星的崎岖地形
the astronauts will also need a vehicle that can deal with the roughest of terrains
NASA也专门为此一直在开发“太空探索载具”(SEV)
NASA have been developing the “Space Exploration Vehicle” for this exact purpose
这是一个加压载具，可供4名宇航员待上72小时
This is a pressurized vehicle which can support up to 4 astronauts for 72 hours
在火星上有几辆这种SEV
With multiple SEV’s on the surface of Mars
宇航员最远能行驶125英里(200千米)
it would allow astronauts to travel more than 125 miles in any direction
这比当年月球车最远只能走6英里(9656米)强多了
a major leap forward from the maximum 6 mile range that the lunar rover had on the moon
所以随着我们离人类去火星的日子越来越近
So as we get closer to seeing the first humans set foot on Mars
请不要忘记这背后人们克服的无数工程挑战
we can appreciate the enormous engineering challenges that need to be overcome before they get there
也感谢给给虫充电的同学
如果喜欢这个视频，欢迎到下面链接去资瓷一下
If you enjoyed this video and would like to contribute to Primal Space, please visit Patreon.com/PrimalSpace
YouTuber那边的Patreon攒够50人后会送乐高版土星五号哦~
where we will be doing a giveaway of a Saturn V Lego set, once we reach 50 Patreon!
记得关注YouTuber频道Primal Space，带你了解和太空有关的知识
So make sure you’re subscribed so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space
字幕翻译给虫，记得投币点赞关注收藏分享转发哦
Thank you very much for watching and I’ll see you in the next video